<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>SJTU Events</title><description>coming up</description><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/calendar.html</link><item><title>Designed Chemical Synthesis and Assembly of Uniform-sized Nanoparticles for Medical and Energy Applications </title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1901-designed-chemical-synthesis-and-assembly-of-uniform-sized-nanoparticles-for-medical-and-energy-applications</link><description>Date: Monday, November 02, 2015, 14:00&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Prof. Taeghwan Hyeon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#65292;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Director of Center for Nanoparticle Research, Institute for Basic Science (IBS)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#65292;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Associate Editor of J. Am. Chem. Soc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#65292;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;SNU Distinguished Fellow (Distinguished University Professor)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#65292;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;School of Chemical and Biological Engineering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#65292;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Seoul National University&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Room 518 of Building A at School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Topic: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Designed Chemical Synthesis and Assembly of Uniform-sized Nanoparticles for Medical and Energy Applications &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Invited by: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Prof. Shun'ai Che &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Abstract: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Over the last 10 years, our laboratory has focused on the designed chemical synthesis, assembly and applications of uniform-sized nanocrystals. In particular, we developed a novel generalized procedure called as the &amp;ldquo;heat-up process&amp;rdquo; for the direct synthesis of uniform-sized nanocrystals of many metals, oxides, and chalcogenides.(1)&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Recently our group has been focused on medical applications of various uniform-sized nanoparticles. Using 3 nm-sized iron oxide nanoparticles, new non-toxic MRI contrast agent was realized for high resolution MRI of blood vessels down to 0.2 mm.(2) We reported the first successful demonstration of high-resolution in vivo three-photon imaging using biocompatible and bright Mn2+ doped ZnS nanocrystals.(3) We fabricated tumor pH-sensitive magnetic nanogrenades composed of self-assembled iron oxide nanoparticles and pH-responsive ligands for theranostic application, enabling the visualization of small tumors of &amp;lt; 3 mm via pH-responsive T1 MRI and fluorescence imaging and superior photodynamic therapeutic efficacy in highly drug-resistant heterogeneous tumors.(4) We synthesized tumor pH-sensitive nanoformulated triptolide coated with folate targeting ligand to treat hepatocellular carcinoma (HCC), which has one of the worst prognosis for survival as it is poorly responsive to both conventional chemotherapy and mechanism directed therapy. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;We reported the large-scale synthesis of magnetite nanocrystals imbedded in a carbon matrix and hollow iron oxide nanoparticles. We demonstrated galvanic replacement reactions in metal oxide nanocrystals. When Mn3O4 nanocrystals were reacted with iron(II) perchlorate, hollow box-shaped nanocrystals of Mn3O4/&amp;gamma;-Fe2O3 (&amp;ldquo;nanoboxes&amp;rdquo;) were produced.(5) These iron oxide-based nanomaterials exhibited very high specific capacity and good cyclability for lithium ion battery anodes. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;1. "Ultra-Large Scale Syntheses of Monodisperse Nanocrystals," Nature Mater. 2004, 3, 891.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;2. &amp;ldquo;Large-scale Synthesis of Uniform and Extremely Small-sized Iron Oxide Nanoparticles for High-resolution T1 MRI Contrast Agents,&amp;rdquo; J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2011, 133, 12624.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;3. &amp;ldquo;High-Resolution Three-Photon Biomedical Imaging using Doped ZnS Nanocrystals,&amp;rdquo; Nature Mater. 2013, 12, 359. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;4. &amp;ldquo;Multifunctional Tumor pH-Sensitive Self-Assembled Nanoparticles for Bimodal Imaging and Treatment of Resistant Heterogeneous Tumors,&amp;rdquo; J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2014, 136, 5647.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;5. &amp;ldquo;Galvanic Replacement Reactions in Metal Oxide Nanocrystals,&amp;rdquo; Science 2013, 340, 964. Highlighted in &amp;ldquo;Perspectives: All Change for Nanocrystals,&amp;rdquo; Science 2013, 340, 935. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Biography: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10px;"&gt;Taeghwan Hyeon received his B.S. (1987) &amp;amp; M.S.(1989) in Chemistry from Seoul National University (SNU), and Ph.D. in Chemistry from U. Illinois (1996). Since he joined School of Chemical and Biological Engineering of SNU in 1997, he has been focused on synthesis and applications of uniform-sized nanoparticles, and published &amp;gt; 250 papers in prominent international journals. In 2010, he was appointed as the first &amp;ldquo;SNU Distinguished Fellow.&amp;rdquo; In 2012, he was appointed as a Director of Center for Nanoparticle Research of Institute for Basic Science. He is Fellow of Royal Society of Chemistry and Materials Research Society. He received many awards including Hoam Prize (2012, Samsung Hoam Foundation), POSCO-T. J. Park Award (2008), Presidential Young Scientist Award (2002), and DuPont Sci&amp;amp;Tech Award (2005). Since 2010, he has served as an Associate Editor of J. Am. Chem. Soc.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 01:46:51 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">1c0dc694-7083-11e5-bb50-000000000000</guid></item><item><title>Dynamic Structures and Properties of Porous Coordination Polymers/Metal-Organic Frameworks. </title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1900-dynamic-structures-and-properties-of-porous-coordination-polymers-metal-organic-frameworks</link><description>Date: Wednesday, October 28, 2015, 14:00&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Prof. Susumu KITAGAWA, Institute for Integrated Cell-Material Sciences, Department of Synthetic Chemistry and Biological Chemistry, Kyoto University, Japan&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;The Meeting Room on the Fifth Floor of Building A at School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Topic:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Dynamic Structures and Properties of Porous Coordination Polymers/Metal-Organic Frameworks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Invited by:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Prof. Shun'ai Che&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Abstract: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;The recent advent of porous coordination polymers (PCPs) or metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) as new functional microporous materials, have attracted the attention of chemists and physicists due to not only scientific but also application interest in the creation of unprecedented regular nano-sized spaces and in the finding of novel phenomena.1-3 The recent advent of porous coordination polymers (PCPs) or metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) as new functional microporous materials, have attracted the attention of chemists and physicists due to not only scientific but also application interest in the creation of unprecedented regular nano-sized spaces and in the finding of novel phenomena.1-3 We have found flexible porous frameworks, which respond to specific guests, dissimilar to the conventional porous materials.4 This new class of materials encompasses possibility creating platform for porous functions. In this talk, three noteworthy properties (flexibility and softness, collectivity of spaces, and diverse structures) are emphasized as they should become increasingly more important as this material is developed. In addition, we have focused on mesoscopic domains and/or whole size of PCP crystals, and discovered unique functions regarding confinement, recognition, transportation and conversion of guest molecules, and responsiveness to chemical and/or physical stimuli.1-5 Based on the unique properties we would be able to apply PCPs to gas materials since low molecular weight molecules, such as carbon dioxide (CO2), hydrogen (H2), oxygen (O2), methane (CH4), acetylene (C2H2), nitric oxide (NO) and alkanes (C2&amp;ndash;C3), are important gases for the global issues of energy, natural resources, the environment, and living systems. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Reference:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;1) S. Horike, et.al., Nature Chem., 2009, 1, 695. &lt;br /&gt; 2) H. Sato, et.al., Nature Mater., 2010, 9, 661. &lt;br /&gt; 3) Y. Sakata, et.al., Science, 2013, 339, 193. &lt;br /&gt; 4) S. Diring, et.al., Nature Commun., 2013, 4, 2684. &lt;br /&gt; 5) H. Sato, et.al., Science, 2014, 343, 167.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 01:46:00 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">fd51791c-7082-11e5-b2df-000000000000</guid></item><item><title>New Interaction of Asymmetric Organocatalysis with Theoretical Chemistry </title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1904-new-interaction-of-asymmetric-organocatalysis-with-theoretical-chemistry</link><description>Date: Monday, October 26, 2015, 13:00&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Prof. Keiji Maruoka&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Lecture Hall on the Fifth Floor of Building A at School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Topic: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;New Interaction of Asymmetric Organocatalysis with Theoretical Chemistry&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Invited by:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Prof. Yongqiang Tu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 16:27:03 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">3b3b02f6-767e-11e5-ba66-000000000000</guid></item><item><title>Lignocellulosic biomass research at QUT </title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1898-lignocellulosic-biomass-research-at-qut</link><description>Date: Friday, October 23, 2015, 15:00&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Dr. Jan Zhanying Zhang, Centre for Tropical Crops and Biocommodities, Queensland University of Technology, Australia &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;The Lecture Hall on the Fifth Floor of Building A at School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Topic: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Lignocellulosic biomass research at QUT &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Invited by: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Prof. Xinyuan Zhu and Prof. Jianjiang Zhong &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Abstract: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Production of valuable and sustainable fuels, chemicals and materials from lignocellulosic biomass has attracted increasing interest worldwide. The researchers at Queensland University of Technology (QUT) are dedicated to development of technically and economically feasible processes for biomass conversion and utilisation. These biomass conversion processes include thermal-chemical and biological processes. In this presentation, Dr Zhanying Zhang will introduce the research progress in the area of biomass research at QUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 11:07:16 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">96ac8a38-5ebe-11e5-a10f-000000000000</guid></item><item><title>Polymer nanocomposites for engineering and biomedical applications</title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1903-polymer-nanocomposites-for-engineering-and-biomedical-applications</link><description>Date: Thursday, October 22, 2015, 16:00&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Dr. Biqiong Chen, Senior Lecturer in Polymer Science, Department of Materials Science and Engineering, University of Sheffield, UK&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Room 129 of Building A at School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Topic:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Polymer nanocomposites for engineering and biomedical applications&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Invited by&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;: Prof. Yong Zhang &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Abstract&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Polymer nanocomposites have been a subject of research and innovation interests over the last two decades because additions of a small amount of nanoparticles, typically less than 10 wt.%, can provide significant enhancements on properties including mechanical, thermal and barrier properties. In this talk, I will give a brief introduction to the field of polymer nanocomposites and discuss our recent work on these materials. In particular, I will endeavor to explain why the presence of layered-structured nanoparticles such as clay and graphene in polymer matrices can improve the strength, stiffness, ductility and toughness concurrently, which is highly attractive in engineering applications. I will also introduce our recent research on the development of water-responsive polymer nanocomposites with shape-memory effects, biodegradable polymer nanocomposites, and nanocomposite foams and hydrogels for biomedical applications such as minimally invasive medical devices, tissue scaffolds and drug delivery.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Biography&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Biqiong Chen received her BSc from Donghua University, MSc from Shanghai Jiao Tong University and PhD from the University of London. Following her postdocotral research in London, she worked at Trinity College Dublin as a Lecturer (Assistant Professor) during 2008-2012. She is currently a Senior Lecturer (Associate Professor) at the Universit yof Sheffield, leading the Polymer Nanocomposites Research Group in the Department of Materials Science and Engineering. Her research is focused on polymer nanocomposites, aiming to gain a better understanding of these materials and to explore their potential applications in engineering, energy and healthcare. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Department of Materials Science and Engineering, University of Sheffield, Mappin Street, Sheffield S1 3JD, United Kingdom. Email: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:biqiong.chen@sheffield.ac.uk"&gt;&lt;span&gt;biqiong.chen@sheffield.ac.uk&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 16:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">1ebcbdfe-767e-11e5-8722-000000000000</guid></item><item><title>The regulatory circuit of virulence factors in Erwinia amylovora </title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1902-the-regulatory-circuit-of-virulence-factors-in-erwinia-amylovora</link><description>Date: Tuesday, October 20, 2015, 09:00&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Youfu Zhao &amp;nbsp;Department of Crop Sciences, University of Illinois&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Room 105 of Building 3 at School of Life Sciences and Biotechnology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Topic: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;The regulatory circuit of virulence factors in Erwinia amylovora&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Contact: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;&amp;nbsp;He Yawen&amp;nbsp; Email: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:yawenhe@sjtu.edu.cn"&gt;&lt;span&gt;yawenhe@sjtu.edu.cn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Abstract: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;The apple and pear industry in the U. S. and around the world has been devastated by fire blight disease caused by Erwinia amylovora. Extensive genetic studies have demonstrated that a functional hypersensitive response and pathogenicity (hrp) - type III secretion system (T3SS) and its associated effectors as well as production of the exopolysaccharide amylovoran are primary determinants in E. amylovora to cause fire blight disease. Recent studies in my lab have demonstrated that two-component signal transduction systems and sigma factors in E. amylovora play significant roles in regulating T3SS and amylovoran production both at transcriptional and post-transcriptional levels. Novel regulatory systems, such as bacterial second nucleotide messengers and RNA-binding proteins, are also found to be critical in controlling virulence factors. These findings suggest that E. amylovora has developed complicated regulatory networks or circuits to tightly control major virulence factors. In this presentation, recent findings utilizing genetics and omics approaches to understand E. amylovora virulence will be summarized and highlighted. Future perspectives and research directions for this important pathogen as well as other plant pathogenic bacteria will also be discussed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 16:25:33 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">058404dc-767e-11e5-8722-000000000000</guid></item><item><title>Palladium Meets Gold: Peculiar Activity of Bimetallic Gold/Palladium Alloy Nanoclusters </title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1899-palladium-meets-gold-peculiar-activity-of-bimetallic-gold-palladium-alloy-nanoclusters</link><description>Date: Thursday, October 15, 2015, 16:00&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Professor Hidehiro SAKURAI, Division of Applied Chemistry, School of Engineering&lt;br /&gt; Osaka University&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;The Lecture Hall on the Fifth Floor of Building A at School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Topic: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Palladium Meets Gold: Peculiar Activity of Bimetallic Gold/Palladium Alloy Nanoclusters&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Invited by: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Prof. Wanbin Zhang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Biography: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Hidehiro SAKURAI&lt;br /&gt; Professor, &lt;br /&gt; Division of Applied Chemistry, School of Engineering&lt;br /&gt; Osaka University&lt;br /&gt; Email: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:hsakurai@chem.eng.osaka-u.ac.jp"&gt;&lt;span&gt;hsakurai@chem.eng.osaka-u.ac.jp&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;MEMBERSHIP OF SOCIETIES:&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Chemical Society of Japan&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp; American Chemical Society&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;EDUCATIONAL CAREER&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;1985-1989&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Department of Chemistry, The University of Tokyo&lt;br /&gt; 1989-1994&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Graduate School of Science, The University of Tokyo &amp;nbsp; (Supervisor: Professor Koichi Narasaka)&lt;br /&gt; 1994&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Ph. D (The University of Tokyo)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;ACADEMIC CAREER&lt;br /&gt; 1992-1994&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;JSPS doctoral fellow, The University of Tokyo (Professor Koichi Narasaka)&lt;br /&gt; 1994-1996&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Assistant Professor, The University of Tokyo &lt;br /&gt; 1996-1998&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; JSPS postdoctoral fellow, University of Wisconsin (Professor Charles P. Casey)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;1998-2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Assistant Professor, The University of Tokyo &lt;br /&gt; 2000-2004&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Associate Professor, Osaka University&lt;br /&gt; 2004-2014&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Associate Professor, Institute for Molecular Science&lt;br /&gt; 2007-2011&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;JST-PRESTO researcher &lt;br /&gt; 2012-present &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;PI of JST-ACT-C Project&lt;br /&gt; 2014-present &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Professor, Osaka University&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;AWARD&lt;br /&gt; 2013 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; IUPAC Distinguished Award on Novel Materials and their Synthesis &lt;br /&gt; 2014 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The CSJ Award for Creative Work&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;CURRNT RESEARCH FIELD&lt;br /&gt; 1. Synthesis and Properties of non-planar aromatic compounds &amp;ldquo;Buckybowls&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt; 2. Development of metal nanocluster catalyst&lt;br /&gt;3. Synthesis and reactions of organometallic compounds&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 01:45:15 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">e252da8e-7082-11e5-95c5-000000000000</guid></item><item><title>Polymer Reaction Engineering and Advanced Materials </title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1896-polymer-reaction-engineering-and-advanced-materials</link><description>Date: Tuesday, October 13, 2015, 09:30&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Prof. Zhu Shiping, Fellow of Canadian Academy of Engineering and the Academy of Science of the Royal Society of Canada&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Room 518 of Building A at School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Invited by: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10px;" lang="EN-US"&gt;Prof. Zhenghong Luo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 11:05:12 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">4c6031a0-5ebe-11e5-b992-000000000000</guid></item><item><title>The role of surfactants in achieving high-fidelity separations of single walled carbon nanotubes (SWCNTs) </title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1895-the-role-of-surfactants-in-achieving-high-fidelity-separations-of-single-walled-carbon-nanotubes-swcnts</link><description>Date: Wednesday, September 30, 2015, 09:30&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Dr. Kirk J Ziegler, Associate Professor, Department of Chemical Engineering, University of Florida &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Room 410 of Building B at School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Topic: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;The role of surfactants in achieving high-fidelity separations of single walled carbon nanotubes (SWCNTs) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Invited by:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt; Prof. Kaixue Wang&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Abstract: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;The high surface area of nanomaterials dictates that the interface with their surroundings is important in determining their properties or functionality. For example, all atoms in single-walled carbon nanotubes (SWCNTs) exist on the surface and, therefore, have excellent sensing capabilities. The interface of SWCNTs with their surroundings is also important to their application in polymer composites, devices, drug delivery, bioimaging and biosensing. Understanding and ultimately controlling these surface layers is important because of its influence on reactivity, adsorption of pollutants, and interaction with biological materials. SWCNT interfaces are often altered with surfactants to improve their dispersion in aqueous suspensions. While the surfactant surrounding the nanotube provides many benefits, the inability to alter or control this interface often limits the performance or functionality of the nanotube. A lack of information on the effect of the surrounding environment on SWCNT properties further complicates the development of processes to control these interfaces. Our group has focused on characterizing and controlling SWCNT interfaces. The ability to reorganize the surfactant structure surrounding SWCNTs is achieved through both chemical and mechanical manipulations. Using our understanding of the surfactant structure surrounding SWCNTs, we have shown that the surfactant orientation on the SWCNT surface is an important parameter during the selective adsorption of semiconducting SWCNTs onto agarose gels. Understanding the mechanism behind these separations has enabled high-fidelity separations based on a single elution profile in a single column. The structure of the surfactant or other molecules around the SWCNTs also has important implications in toxicology. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Biography:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Dr. Ziegler completed his Ph.D. in Chemical Engineering at the University of Texas at Austin. He then received the Enterprise Ireland Postdoctoral Fellowship and conducted research at University College Cork followed by postdoctoral research at Rice University with Nobel Laureate Richard Smalley. In 2005, Professor Ziegler joined the faculty in the Chemical Engineering Department at the University of Florida. His research group focuses on understanding the role of interfaces in one-dimensional nanostructures, such as SWCNTs and vertical arrays of nanowires.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 11:04:24 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">2fc3c26e-5ebe-11e5-a10f-000000000000</guid></item><item><title>Publishing in Materials Science </title><link>http://en.sjtu.edu.cn/events/1897-publishing-in-materials-science</link><description>Date: Wednesday, September 30, 2015, 09:30&lt;br/&gt;Location: Minhang&lt;br/&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Speaker: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Dr. Xin Su, Associate Editor of Wiley Journals (Adv. Mater., J. Polym. Sci. Part A: Polym. Chem., J. Polym. Sci. Part B: Polym. Phys., J. Appl. Polym. Sci.) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Where: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;The Lecture Hall on the Fifth Floor of Building A at School of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Topic: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Publishing in Materials Science &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Invited by: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Prof. Deyue Yan and Prof. Xinyuan Zhu &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Abstract:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Materials science is a multidisciplinary research field with many different kinds of scientists and engineers active in it. The literature landscape is consequently populated by a range of journals which greatly differ in purpose, scope, quality, and readership. After an introduction on Wiley's publishing activities and Asia's changing global role in materials science, the lecture focuses on successful publishing in this complex environment. What can prospective authors do to optimize their chances of success? Key aspects are: structuring one's research work well, understanding the decision processes in editorial offices, choosing an appropriate journal, assembling a convincing manuscript, knowing what to put in the cover letter, and which things to avoid. In addition, the talk covers publishing ethics, best practice for authors and reviewers, the reasoning behind peer review, and editorial workflows. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Biography: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Xin Su studied chemistry at and received his B.Sc. from Nankai University (Tianjin, China) in 2009, where he carried out research on water-soluble calixarenes. He then started his graduate research on hydrazone-based functional materials at Dartmouth College (Hanover, NH, USA), and received his PhD in Organic Chemistry in 2013. After working at the National Energy Technology Laboratory (Pittsburgh, PA, USA) as an Oak Ridge Institute for Science and Education (ORISE) Postdoctoral Fellow, he joined Wiley's Hoboken office (New Jersey, USA) in 2015 as an Associate Editor in Materials Science. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span lang="EN-US"&gt;Xin currently manages day-to-day peer review processes for Advanced Materials, and contributes to the editorial management of Journal of Polymer Science Part A: Polymer Chemistry, Journal of Polymer Science Part B: Polymer Physics, and Journal of Applied Polymer Science. Xin writes research highlights for MaterialsViews and ChemistryViews, Wiley&amp;rsquo;s materials science and chemistry news portals, respectively.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 10px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 11:06:09 +0000</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">6ea144ca-5ebe-11e5-a10f-000000000000</guid></item></channel></rss>